### **Software Development Engineer in Test**

Varshitha heights, Bangalore - 560043 | 9731227136 | akshay.ca42@gmail.com

### Career Objective

Currently working as a R&D Quality Assurance Engineer at **Dassault Systèmes** with 2.9 years of total experience. Looking for a position in SDET, R&D QA, Test Automation Engineer in Python, C#, JavaScript or JAVA, where I can apply my skills and experience to support the project growth, improve my skills and add values.

#### **Skills & Abilities**

Expertise in **Object-Oriented Programming** (OOP), building different UI Automation Testing frameworks, Behavior Driven Development (**BDD**)- **Cucumber**, TDD, Selenium, **Mobile Testing**, **API testing**, Quality Analysis, preparing test plans/test strategy, test closure, status reports, **GIT**, **Agile methodologies-** SCRUM, **DevOps** (CI/CD) with Jenkins and Microsoft Azure DevOps, Performance and Security testing (Basics). Knowledge of Insurance domain and with **good communication skills**.

ISTQB, CP-SAT and IBM Data Science certified.

# Programming language

Python, JS, C#, JAVA and MySQL.

## Framework and Tools

Selenium WebDriver, SpecFlow, Cucumber- BDD, Page Object Model (POM), NUnit, XUnit, TestNG, pytest, JasmineJS, LeetCode.

Appium, GIT, Jenkins, SoapUI, Extent Reports,

Visual Studio and VS Code, Eclipse, Microsoft Azure Team Foundation Server (TFS) and Office products.

#### **Experience**

#### R&D Quality Assurance Engineer at Dassault Systèmes

(April 2020 – Present)

It is a is a French software company that develops 3D design, 3D digital mock-up, and Product lifecycle management software.

### Project: ENOVIA Product Lifecycle Management (PLM) software

- Review the documents received for R&D. So, that the same can be shared with authorities and customers.
   Ensure proper Stage Gate compliance at every stage of product development.
- Worked on maintenance of existing Automation test framework built with the help of Sahi and Sikuli.
- Working on implementation and development of new Automation framework using JavaScript and JasmineJS.

#### SDET at Larsen & Toubro Infotech (LTI)

(September 2017 – April 2020)
It is a global IT solutions and services company.

#### Project: BB&T- Bank holding company

BB&T acts as a third-party agent that assists in selling of insurance policies of various insurance companies in return for a percentage in form of commission.

- Sole ownership of Automation in two complex projects, Introduced BDD- Cucumber and developed UI Automation framework from scratch.
- Built using SpecFlow with Selenium and C# for Direct
   Billing System and Python for Carrier Payable System Web application using POM design pattern.
- Followed pure SCRUM Agile methodology, active participation in Daily Scrum/Standup, Sprint Planning, Backlog refinement, Sprint Retrospective Meetings.
- Efficiently performed testing for biweekly releases pertaining to enhancements, change requests and defects.
- Used Microsoft Azure TFS for reporting, requirements management, project management, automated builds and release management capabilities. GIT for source code management.

Akshay CA

Software Development Engineer in Test

# Certifications And Trainings

<u>ISTQB - International Software Testing Qualifications Board</u>

CP-SAT - Certified Professional – Selenium Automation Testing

IBM Data Science Professional Certificate

Machine Learning with Python

#### Achievements

Client appreciation e-mails for consistent good work under

BB&T and MMC Projects. Successfully demonstrated

Automation framework on Client Visit.

Received "Pat on the Back" award and rated "Outstanding

Performer" in LTI annual appraisal.

#### **Education**

#### **Information Science Engineering**

2013-2017

#### PES Institute of Technology – Bangalore

- Built a game with the Unity3D Game Engine and C# as a part of Final year project "Prerak Kala - Art of persuasion".
- Was part of College Basketball Team.
- Active member of Creative Department Maaya.

## Hobbies and Interests

Basketball, Sketching, Reading, New-age testing - that use Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning and big data.

#### Contact Me

GitHub - Personal portfolio,

LinkedIn